# Siyad Adan

<u>siyad.adan94@gmail.com</u> • Ottawa, ON github.com/siyad-adan/ • linkedin.com/in/siyadadan/ • siyadadan.dev

# **Summary Statement**

Software engineer with B.S in Computer Science and 3+ years' experience. Microsoft Azure Data Engineer certified. A track record of optimizing data flows for interconnected projects by 30x and redesigning monolithic software to multi-distributed which decreased installation times by 3x. Also, developing leadership skills by mentoring undergraduate 1st and 2nd year computer science students.

## **Education**

## Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Major, CO-OP Option

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON September 2018 – February 2022

- 4.0/4.0 GPA
- David A. Golden Scholarship Recipient

### **Bachelor of Applied Science, Chemical Engineering**

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON September 2013 – August 2018

• 3.7/4.0 GPA

## **Work Experience**

# **Software Developer**

Apption, Ottawa, Ontario

January 2021 -Present

- Lead development of Canada Soccer (CS) projects, such as website, National Registry REST API, and Club Licensing System
- Created and prototyped data obfuscation algorithm for the data discovery and classification software <u>Datahunter</u>
- Tested, coded, reviewed, and delivered software with 100% on-time record for client-driven Canada Soccer projects
- Leveraged Azure services to optimize data flows for interconnected CS projects which increased data delivery by 30x

# **Software Developer**

Barracuda Networks, Ottawa, Ontario

January 2020 - August 2020

- Decoupled and refactored .NET Framework-based MSP software code base into separate projects for architectural change
- Developed Jenkins installation pipeline to install MSP software in multi-distributed system
- Redesigned MSP software from monolithic to multi distributed system which decreased installation time by 3x

#### **Software Developer**

Konnexis, Ottawa, Ontario

May 2019 - August 2019

- Developed .NET Framework-based localization tool to convert excel translation files to XML for master XML translation file
- Implemented and tested developer utility tools for software development team which increased productivity by 3x

#### Skills

Languages: C#, JavaScript, PHP, T-SQL, Python

Technologies: .NET, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, React, Git, Azure, Jenkins, YAML, WordPress, PowerShell Scripting, SSMS

# Certifications

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate, August 2021
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, May 2021